<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Life Journal : Ishita Jain</title><link>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Life Journal : Ishita Jain</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 08:30:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ishita-jain19.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Musical Revelation</title><link>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/a-musical-revelation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 08:30:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/a-musical-revelation/</guid><description>Today, let me reminisce about a childhood memory when I embarked on the journey of learning classical singing. It was a day that marked a pivotal moment in my musical endeavors.
After a few classes with a talented teacher who played the harmonium, my friend and I, the two eager students, were absorbed in the world of musical notes. However, my friend excelled, showcasing a natural aptitude, while my own progress fell short of expectations.</description></item><item><title>Sibling bonds</title><link>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/sibling-bonds/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 08:30:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/sibling-bonds/</guid><description>In our usual fashion, my brother and I engaged in frequent fights and arguments during our younger days. As he grew older, his curiosity often led him to touch and disrupt my meticulously organized belongings, sparking my frustration. One particular day stands out vividly in my memory. 😄
On that day, he wreaked havoc on the dollhouse I had been diligently crafting and even broke the head of my beloved Barbie doll—a common target for mischievous brothers, it seems.</description></item><item><title>Maiden Skies: A Himalayan Flight Tale</title><link>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/maiden-skies-a-himalayan-flight-tale/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 08:30:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/maiden-skies-a-himalayan-flight-tale/</guid><description>Today, I want to share the enchanting memory of my inaugural flight experience. 😛 It marked the first time I soared through the skies, taking a small flight from Kathmandu, Nepal, to Pokhara, Nepal—a brief 20-minute journey with breathtaking views of the majestic Himalayas.
Approximately 23 years ago, there was only one plane operating on this route, a small, few-seater aircraft. 😃 The airports at both ends lacked modern amenities, relying entirely on manual processes.</description></item><item><title>Summit of Love: A Valentine's Day Ascent to Remember</title><link>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/a-valentines-day-ascent-to-remember/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 08:30:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/a-valentines-day-ascent-to-remember/</guid><description>Over the past 12 years, amidst the multitude of memories, ups, and downs with my husband, there&amp;rsquo;s one particular day that stands out, making our bond stronger. On this Valentine&amp;rsquo;s Day, I feel compelled to share this extraordinary experience, etched with emotions of love and resilience. ❤️❤️
It was the day we conquered Mount Kinabalu, the highest peak in South East Asia. The anticipation and excitement were palpable as we embarked on this adventure together.</description></item><item><title>High Tea, Laughter, and Unforgettable Bonds</title><link>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/high-tea-laughter-and-unforgettable-bonds/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 08:30:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/high-tea-laughter-and-unforgettable-bonds/</guid><description>On a lovely, spontaneous day, my daughter&amp;rsquo;s beloved friend, almost like an elder sister, graced us with her presence on a weekend. 😊 It unfolded as a leisurely, delightful day filled with scrumptious food prepared by our helper, lounging on the bed engrossed in the pages of &amp;lsquo;Palace of Illusion,&amp;rsquo; and the kids happily playing outdoors.
To fulfill the girls&amp;rsquo; desire for high tea, I ordered croissants and scones. As the evening approached, we gathered on our balcony for a small high tea, sharing laughter over the school gossip.</description></item><item><title>A Vacation Tale of Joy, Regret, and Family Bonding</title><link>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/a-vacation-tale-of-joy-regret-and-family-bonding/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 08:30:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/a-vacation-tale-of-joy-regret-and-family-bonding/</guid><description>After completing my 10th board exams, my maternal side family embarked on an exciting trip to one of my aunt&amp;rsquo;s house in Gujarat—a time filled with joy, new experiences, and the company of beloved cousins.
On this specific day, as my elder cousin brother and I prepared ourselves, the rest of the family readied for the day&amp;rsquo;s exploration. He suggested, &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to ride a 2-wheeler, let&amp;rsquo;s take a spin while the others get ready.</description></item><item><title>The Sweet Imitation of a Toddler's Innocence</title><link>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/the-sweet-imitation-of-a-toddlers-innocence/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 08:30:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/the-sweet-imitation-of-a-toddlers-innocence/</guid><description>Today, I want to share a heartwarming memory that unexpectedly surfaced in my Google Photos, filling my heart with warmth and joy.
Back when my daughter was just 2 years and a few months old, we were all gathered on the bed one day. Out of the blue, she started playfully mimicking sleep, closing her tiny hands, folding them around her chest, shutting her eyes, and pretending to fall in different directions.</description></item><item><title>A Sick Day's Unexpected Twist</title><link>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/a-sick-days-unexpected-twist/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 08:30:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/a-sick-days-unexpected-twist/</guid><description>Today, I&amp;rsquo;m eager to share a delightful incident from this morning&amp;rsquo;s breakfast that kept me smiling throughout the day.
Last night, my daughter fell ill, developing a fever that persisted till morning. Recognizing her discomfort, my husband and I decided to let her rest and skip school for the day. Although she was enthusiastic about the upcoming Chinese New Year celebration at school, featuring her dance performance, we believed a day off would do her good.</description></item><item><title>Lessons from a Childhood Cultural Program - From Tree to Triumph (Part2)</title><link>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/from-tree-to-triumph/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 08:30:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/from-tree-to-triumph/</guid><description>Today, let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the aftermath of the day I shared in my previous blog post, where my heart sank at being cast as a tree in a play, leading me to contemplate quitting.
As I woke up the next morning, my determination to quit the play was unwavering. Ready for school, my mum continued her efforts to talk me out of it, but my distress and resolve prevailed. 😞</description></item><item><title>Lessons from a Childhood Cultural Program</title><link>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/lessons-from-a-childhood-cultural-program/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 08:30:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/lessons-from-a-childhood-cultural-program/</guid><description>Today, I want to share a memory that holds a somewhat melancholic place in my recollection. When I was around 11 years old, in standard 6, my school was celebrating its 75th anniversary, and a grand cultural program was in the works. The event promised a plethora of dances, acts, and performances by students across all grades. At that time, I had a keen interest in dramatics and eagerly wished to participate in the play that Standard 6 was slated to perform.</description></item><item><title>A Spelling Test Tale from Childhood</title><link>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/a-spelling-test-tale-from-childhood/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 08:30:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/a-spelling-test-tale-from-childhood/</guid><description>I don&amp;rsquo;t remember the day very well since it happened when I was 4 to 5 years old. However, my mum has talked about this day a few times, which always makes me smile. 😊
I came back from school, and I had a spelling test that day. After returning home, my mum asked me about the test. I happily shared that it went well, except for one word I knew was wrong.</description></item><item><title>Culinary Adventures and Lessons Learned</title><link>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/culinary-adventures-and-lessons-learned/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 08:30:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/culinary-adventures-and-lessons-learned/</guid><description>The day I want to share today is post my move to Singapore. After settling down in Singapore following my marriage, about four months later, my husband and I planned a short trip to Melaka, a city in Malaysia approximately 4 hours away by road. This plan coincided with the Christmas holidays, and I was filled with excitement as it marked my first visit to a new country, the fourth overall, including India and Singapore.</description></item><item><title>A Tale of Frosty Feet and Unexpected Lessons</title><link>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/a-tale-of-frosty-feet-and-unexpected-lessons/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 08:30:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/a-tale-of-frosty-feet-and-unexpected-lessons/</guid><description>Today, I reminisce about a day from our family trip to Darjeeling, a journey embarked upon when I was around 9 years old, accompanied by a delightful group of family friends. This adventure, etched in my childhood memories, has become a cornerstone of my passion for travel — a gift from my parents that I am forever grateful for. ❤️ ❤️
We ventured into Darjeeling during the December holidays, immersing ourselves in the freezing cold of a region unaccustomed to winters.</description></item><item><title>A Haircut and Healing Journey</title><link>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/a-haircut-and-healing-journey/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 08:30:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/a-haircut-and-healing-journey/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s delve into a day etched in my memory, a chapter from when I was around 10 years old, battling a month-long struggle with a urinary infection and Typhoid that left me weakened, with persistent fever and troubling symptoms. 😞 This health ordeal unfolded during a holiday, amidst a wedding celebration, and coincided with my long, painstaking effort to grow and maintain healthy hair locks. ❤️
As the infections took a toll on my body, internal weakness set in, leading to weight loss and severe hair fall.</description></item><item><title>A Childhood Tale of Aunt's Surprise Visit</title><link>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/a-childhood-tale-of-aunts-surprise-visit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 08:30:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/a-childhood-tale-of-aunts-surprise-visit/</guid><description>In my tender years, around the age of 4 or 5, the anticipation of my aunt&amp;rsquo;s (my mum&amp;rsquo;s younger sister) visit filled me with excitement. She was unmarried and young, making her visits particularly special as I looked forward to the pampering and quality time we&amp;rsquo;d share. ❤️😇
Prior to her arrival, my mum prepared the guest room. Given our recent move to a new city and the absence of an extra bed, we borrowed a single bed from our thoughtful neighbors.</description></item><item><title>The Day I Wished for a Baby Brother</title><link>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/the-day-i-wished-for-a-baby-brother/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 08:30:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/the-day-i-wished-for-a-baby-brother/</guid><description>This day I fondly remember holds a special place in my heart.
Around the age of 4, I visited a friend who had just welcomed a baby brother. Witnessing her sheer joy and playing with the little one left a lasting impression on me. From that moment, a desire took root – I longed for a baby brother of my own.
Excitedly, I shared my wish with my mother, proposing a visit to the hospital to surprise my dad, who was away at the time.</description></item></channel></rss>