<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Life Journal : Ishita Jain</title><link>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Life Journal : Ishita Jain</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 08:30:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ishita-jain19.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Haircut and Healing Journey</title><link>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/a-haircut-and-healing-journey/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 08:30:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/a-haircut-and-healing-journey/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s delve into a day etched in my memory, a chapter from when I was around 10 years old, battling a month-long struggle with a urinary infection and Typhoid that left me weakened, with persistent fever and troubling symptoms. 😞 This health ordeal unfolded during a holiday, amidst a wedding celebration, and coincided with my long, painstaking effort to grow and maintain healthy hair locks. ❤️
As the infections took a toll on my body, internal weakness set in, leading to weight loss and severe hair fall.</description></item><item><title>A Childhood Tale of Aunt's Surprise Visit</title><link>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/a-childhood-tale-of-aunts-surprise-visit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 08:30:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/a-childhood-tale-of-aunts-surprise-visit/</guid><description>In my tender years, around the age of 4 or 5, the anticipation of my aunt&amp;rsquo;s (my mum&amp;rsquo;s younger sister) visit filled me with excitement. She was unmarried and young, making her visits particularly special as I looked forward to the pampering and quality time we&amp;rsquo;d share. ❤️😇
Prior to her arrival, my mum prepared the guest room. Given our recent move to a new city and the absence of an extra bed, we borrowed a single bed from our thoughtful neighbors.</description></item><item><title>The Day I Wished for a Baby Brother</title><link>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/the-day-i-wished-for-a-baby-brother/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 08:30:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/the-day-i-wished-for-a-baby-brother/</guid><description>This day I fondly remember holds a special place in my heart.
Around the age of 4, I visited a friend who had just welcomed a baby brother. Witnessing her sheer joy and playing with the little one left a lasting impression on me. From that moment, a desire took root – I longed for a baby brother of my own.
Excitedly, I shared my wish with my mother, proposing a visit to the hospital to surprise my dad, who was away at the time.</description></item><item><title>Introduction: Me and my journey</title><link>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/introduction-me-and-my-journey/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 08:30:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ishita-jain19.github.io/posts/introduction-me-and-my-journey/</guid><description>Greetings, everyone!
I&amp;rsquo;m Ishita Jain, originally from India but proud to call Singapore my home for over a decade. By profession, I&amp;rsquo;m a Cyber Security engineer, but my personal passions extend to various forms of creativity, including crafting, cooking, and writing. My love for exploring new countries and cities with my family has allowed me to immerse myself in diverse cultures, traditions, people, and cuisines.
At present, I&amp;rsquo;m on a journey of discovering different ways to embrace life fully.</description></item></channel></rss>